<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes on Ivan Dimitrov</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes on Ivan Dimitrov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 15:20:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best_practices</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/best_practices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 15:20:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/best_practices/</guid><description>With enterprise development, there&amp;rsquo;s something called &amp;ldquo;code maintainability&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s the measure of how easy it is for a given codebase to be maintained by multiple developers at any given time.
When there&amp;rsquo;s new features being added, the complexity of the entire codebase increases. Given enough time, everything can become so complex that the addition of a simple feature, or a simple bug fix, can take multiple times more time than it used to when the code was new.</description></item><item><title>One_thing</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/best_practices/one_thing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 15:19:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/best_practices/one_thing/</guid><description>Object Oriented Programming has a set principles called SOLID. Baeldung has an article on them .
What I want to talk about here is the Single Responsibility Principle. That&amp;rsquo;s the S in SOLID.
As we might expect, this principle states that a class should only have one responsibility. Furthermore, it should only have one reason to change.
I had a discussion about this on some code I was reviewing. These are some CR comments.</description></item><item><title>Audio production</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/unix/audio_production/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 19:49:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/unix/audio_production/</guid><description>This is how you can configure Artix Linux for audio production. The steps should work for any Arch-based linux distro.
tl;dr Run paru -S jack2 pulseaudio pulseaudio-jack qjackctl ardour guitarix a2jmidid pro-audio lv2-plugins.
Run sudo usermod -aG audio $USER.
Create the files with the content inside code blocks below.
Reboot.
Make sure you run the configured pulseaudio and jackd when you want sound.
If you have a MIDI device, run a2jmidid -e to add it as an input device.</description></item><item><title>Unix</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/unix/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 19:20:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/unix/</guid><description>Unix (/ˈjuːnɪks/; trademarked as UNIX) is a family of multitasking, multiuser computer operating systems that derive from the original AT&amp;amp;amp;T Unix, whose development started in 1969[1] at the Bell Labs research center by Ken Thompson, Dennis Ritchie, and others.[4] My Unix operating system of choice is GNU/Linux, which is a free as in libre open-source Unix-based operating system comprised of the Linux kernel and the GNU coreutils .
GNU/Linux comes in many flavours, AKA distributions.</description></item><item><title>Volume</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/suckless/dwmblocks/volume/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 16:59:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/suckless/dwmblocks/volume/</guid><description>My dwmblocks volume script can show the volume and it can set it. It does so for the currently used sink.
For dwmblocks to update the value on the screen I&amp;rsquo;ve set up an update signal so that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get updated every second unnecessarily. There&amp;rsquo;s a keybind for increasing and decreasing the volume that I&amp;rsquo;ve added to my sxhkd config.
super + i volume set -i 5 super + o volume set -d 5 The way it works step by step:</description></item><item><title>Dwmblocks</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/suckless/dwmblocks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 16:35:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/suckless/dwmblocks/</guid><description>dwmblocks is a modular status bar written in c . It is used with dwm to display status bar information.
The status bar is at the top right corner. It shows information like current date, time, weather, network IO, RAM usage and volume. That information gets updated based on predefined rules in your configuration file, which might look something like this:
//Modify this file to change what commands output to your statusbar, and recompile using the make command.</description></item><item><title>Suckless</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/suckless/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 16:07:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/suckless/</guid><description>I know that Java and suckless are like cat and mouse, but hear me out, OK?
Suckless refers to software that&amp;rsquo;s as minimalistic as possible leaving every optional feature out of the final product. That leaves you with a small codebase for each package that&amp;rsquo;s easy to maintain and has less security holes, because of the smaller attack surface compared to bigger projects.
Those smaller packages usually do one thing very well, which means that any additional functionality needs to be provided by a different program.</description></item><item><title>Servers</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/applications/servers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 16:34:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/applications/servers/</guid><description>Being a general purpose programming language, Java can be useful in many ways, including server applications.
Java is mostly used as a web server programming language. Frameworks like Spring Framework are utilised to help build highly scalable and efficient web services. It is used by companies like Google, Netflix, Uber and more.
The code for a basic server is less than 30 lines long.
package uk.co.ivandimitrov; import java.io.BufferedReader; import java.io.InputStreamReader; import java.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/applications/android/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 15:41:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/applications/android/</guid><description>Android is an open source mobile operating system based on a modified version of the Linux kernel created by Google . This is its architecture. We&amp;rsquo;re interested in the APPLICATION FRAMEWORK component, because that&amp;rsquo;s where all the JVM stuff happens. Notice that I said JVM and not Java, because Kotlin is also used in app development.
Android utilises the event-driven architecture to interact with the app user. Programmer-defined EventListeners listen for events and when the appropriate event is fired then all listeners listening for that event execute their business logic.</description></item><item><title>Applications</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/applications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 15:17:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/applications/</guid><description>These are some use cases I&amp;rsquo;ve seen for Java.</description></item><item><title>Java</title><link>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 15:02:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ivandimitrov.co.uk/notes/java/</guid><description>Java is a general purpose programming language designed to run on any platform with the help of the JVM . It is one of the most popular programming languages as of 2022 accorging to Stack Overflow .
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Java for the majority of my professional career. Here are some things that I find interesting.</description></item></channel></rss>